『Thank you, my twilight』— the Pillows
世界必须先被毁灭 之后才能变得美丽
The world must be destroyed before it can become beautiful.
Life, Life is beautiful
生命，生命如此美丽
这是我在心中描绘的世界的愿景
This is the world I envisioned.
僕のルーレット　回り続けてる
我的轮盘 会一直转动下去
这是世界应有的样子
This is how the world should be.
但在这个世界里
But in this world,
只有我的身体在腐烂
only my body is rotting --
She, She is wonderful
她，她是这般美妙
渐渐朽坏
becoming decayed.
没错 它正在朽坏
Yes, decaying.
その瞳に今を映したい
想要让她的眼睛 映照出现在
也许这是我原本该有的样貌
Maybe this is how my body should have been.
也许这才是真正的我
Maybe this is my true self.
迷わないでもぎ取った予感を
毫不犹豫抓住的预感
但我最后还是想起
But then finally, I remember
誰かと待ち合わせてるみたいに
好像在等待着谁似的
我还只是一个初中生
that I'm still only a junior high student,
我并没思考过什么
that I wasn't thinking about anything,
見えたなら間違いじゃない
如果看到就肯定不会有错
还有 这里从不曾发生什么了不起的事情
and that nothing amazing has ever happened here.
一切都是那么平凡
Everything is ordinary.
キミを待ってたんだ
一直在等你
She, She is wonderful
她，她是这般美妙
その瞳に今を映したい
想要让她的眼睛 映照出现在
迷わないでもぎ取った予感を
毫不犹豫抓住的预感
奇跡は起こらなくても充分だぜ
就算不发生奇迹也足够了
今日が最後の日でも
就算今天是最后一天也好
Thank you, my twilight
谢谢你 我的晨曦
闹钟
重　启
本字幕由 SweetSub 制作　仅做交流学习之用途
翻校：ピロピラ ピロコ　其它：tastySugar
停下！
Hold it right there!
要我说多少次呢？
How many times do I have to repeat myself?
在下楼之前 先要说“早上好”
Before you come downstairs, you got to say, "Good morning".
好吧 再来一次
Okay, why don't we give it another go?
三 二 …
Three, two...
酷美 亲爱的 你的傲娇人格每天都在进步
Hidomi, sweetie, you're getting better at that tsundere personality of yours everyday.
你这样子我可以理解
I get that it's a thing you're doing,
但我是你的母亲
but I am your mother,
不管怎样 你还是要对我说“早上好”
so you still have to at least say "good morning" to me.
早饭想吃什么？
What would you like to eat?
我可以在你的早餐里放一点本周的特色菜
I can add some of this week's special to your usual breakfast.
看到了吗？炒纳豆
See? Sautéed natto.
我不想吃早饭
I don't want any.
好吧 那路上小心
'Kay. Then you have a good day.
嗯
Hmm.
在你走之前 ——三 二…
But before you leave -- three, two...
早上好 妈妈
Good morning...Mommy.
-早上好！ -嗯
Morning! Mm-hmm.
早上好，酷美！
Good morning, Hidomi!
嗯…早上好
Mm-hmm...Morning.
“你只是这么挑逗 当然什么也不会出来啊”
"Ch'yeah, well, of course nothing's gonna come out if you keep teasing it like that."
她知道但还是继续缠绕 转动 回旋
And she knew that and kept swirling and twirling and whirling
我宛如在天堂一般
and I was in heaven for eternity, infinity,
不要可怜我
no need to pity me
喂 他没问题吧
Hey, you think he's feeling all right?
井出 你就明白说昨天到底发生什么了吧
Ide, would you just tell us what happened yesterday already?
哦吼吼 你是问我昨天吗？
Oh-ho-ho -- yesterday, you ask?
那个老师昨天在你家过夜的吧
That teacher spend the night at your place, right?
告诉我们到底怎样了
You better tell us what happened.
有些事情需要留下想象的空间
You guys, some things ought to be left to the imagination.
真的假的
For reals?! Seriously?
天啊 恭喜恭喜
No, way. Oh, my gosh. Congratulations.
那当然了
Well, yeah...
说真的吗？
For reals?
还有 你昨天说的那个秘密计划是什么？
By the way, what was the secret plan you were talking about yesterday?
那个嘛？
Oh, that?
到底是什么？
What's that?
艺术展览门票
Art gallery tickets.
什么 艺术？你逗我呢？
Wait, art? For reals?
这可是女人的弱点
Women are total suckers for these kinds of things,
懂不懂啊？
know what I'm saying, boys?
这种东西和你不太搭
This kind of thing doesn't really seem like you.
我用不着擅长这个 可是 当你看着艺术作品的时候
This doesn't have to be my thing. I mean, when you gaze upon art,
你就会情不自禁开始思考这个我们生活的世界甚至是宇宙
you can't help but reflect on the world we live in or the universe.
考察它 从缝隙里窥视它
Like, scrutinize it, peek into it from a gap,
因为 你们懂的 我对那个
because you know me -- I'm interested in the --
怎么说呢 哲学？很有兴趣的
Aw, how do I put it? The...philosophical?
扯吧 你最讨厌这些了
Since when? You hate that stuff.
这是真的！OK 好吧 你们说得对
That's not true! Okay, well, to be honest, you got me.
我不是真的喜欢艺术
I'm not really interested in fine art like this,
但是 想一想 我们两个人能在一个美好的夜晚 一起看美好的东西
but check it -- If the two of us can go have a beautiful night out, looking at beautiful things,
然后 说不定我们的关系就能进一步发展呢？
then who knows? We might be able to deepen our relationship, ya know?
关系？天呐！
Relationship?! I don't believe it!
井出！
Ide!
快说！你打算什么时候进一步发展
Now spill it! When are you making that decision
你们的关系？
about your relationship?!
-你说什么呢？-当然是——！
W-W-W-What do you mean? You know what!
大人的约会
Your adult date.
嘘 森 现在别说这个
Shush, Mori. Let's not talk about that right now.
不如我们来说说你今天的有趣时装吧？
Why don't we talk about your interesting fashion choices today instead?
-嗯 有什么问题吗? - 你怎么会穿着裙子？
Yeah, what about it? Well, what the heck are you doing wearing a skirt?
这是中性装扮 现在时兴这个
It's unisex, and it's in right now.
马可 这是中性 没错吧？
You'd call this unisex, right, Marco?
嗯 对 中性
Huh? Yeah. Unisex.
中性？那是啥？啥？
Unisex? What is that? What?
你居然没听说过 你太过时了
I can't believe you've never heard of it. You are so out of touch.
如果你在时尚界 说出“社会性别”这个词
If you breathe the word "gender" in the fashion world,
会被人丢到老人院
they'll throw you in a nursing home.
-什么？真的？-当然是真的
Wait, for reals? I swear!
现在世界上的潮人都在穿裙子 你不知道吗？
All the hippest guys are wearing skirts nowadays, don't ya know?
马可 这是真的吗？
Marco, is that true?
你的这个睡公园板凳的
Does this mean your old-fart buddies
老古董朋友突然就时尚起来了？
sleeping on park benches are suddenly fashionable?
你说谁老古董呢？
Who are you calling an old fart?!
呃 我不晓得
Well, I don't know.
人应该想穿什么就穿什么
People should be able to wear whatever.
说得对！我说得没错吧？
That's right! I'm right, see?
好好好 随便你
Okay, fine. I really don't care.
但是能不能不要让我看到你的内裤？
Will you just stop showing me your underwear?
我可没有特地露出来给你看
It's not like I'm purposely flashing you.
-看的人是你 -但这在我的视野里
You're the one who's looking. But it's in my view,
人眼会本能地去看出现在视野里的内裤
and one's eye's are instinctively drawn to underwear in their sight.
马可 我说的不对吗？
Right, Marco?
I guess, yeah.
嗯 说的没错
我决不允许你看我的小裤裤
There's absolutely no reason for you to be looking at my panties.
这不是“小裤裤” 这是男用内裤
Don't call them "panties." They are briefs.
你明明随时都可以对着島崎老师的小裤裤看到爽！
Since you can get an eyeful from Miss Shimazaki's panty buffet anytime you want!
■
B班（23）
YOU:  还没有确定是否要参加赏花的
同学，今天截止哦
RYO: 我参加
St: 现在多少人了
YOU: 大约一半（·∞·）
Kaha: 你这什么表情
YOU: 不确定人数随便猜出结果的笑
Eri: 我参加 期待
Sophie: 我也参加 谢谢
Anna: 我去我去 我可以帮忙占位置
YOU:谢谢 也帮忙买东西哦
Sao: 那我占好位置之后也去帮忙
YOU: 好——
大家 跟着我说 早上好
Good morning, everybody. Now repeat after me --
All: Good morning, everybody. Now repeat after me.
请坐
Sit down.
我们原本就坐着
We're already sitting.
棒极——了
Maaarvelous...
满堂红呀
A full house, then.
那就开始上课吧
Now then, to kick off today's class
我先提个问题吧
I would like to pose a question to all of you who are starting
即将开始合理又不幸的新的一天的少年少女们
an understandably regrettable day as members of the current youth.
对你们而言世上最重要的是什么？
What in your estimation is the most important thing in the world to you?
B班（23）
St: 对对 现在还穿着学生服的 233
sao: 为什么说是学生服呢？
St: 特地穿制服的男生也就只有他了
kaho: 真的吗？其它没了？
St: 真的啊 我来上课的时候特地看了
RYO: 你确定没看错？你只是瞟了一眼吧
St: 那个书包 肯定是他没错！
jinno: 书包啊笑 我被说服了
mh: 确实233
mh: 如果是真的这不就糟糕了吗
sao: 太恶心了
kaho: 手呢
St: 不清楚
St: 我只看见了脸
■
对 就是你们 你们是社会上最弱的一环
Yes, you, who are the weakest links in our society.
对 就是你
Yes. You over there.
-我不知道 -回答正确
-I don't know. -Correct answer.
B班（23）
St: 岛酱从破旧的公寓里出来
St: 然后井出也出来了
sao: 岛酱她几岁了来着
kaho: 比他大多了吧
RYO: 她在井出家过夜了？
kaho: 处男毕业!?
St: （>m<）
mh: 哇
sao:  已经不会再继承处男之志了233
jinno: “老师——！”他这么叫的吧
kaho: “岛酱——”什么的吧233
YOU: 和老师搞在一起 真是太恶心了
sao: 不过“岛酱”这个称呼也很土嘛
正合适啦
■
对任何问题都没有清晰的答案
Not having clear and distinct answers for any question
蠢动着自己动物般性欲获得满足
and feeling fulfilled by jerking your animalistic sexual urges --
青春期的你们只知道这样的生活
that is the only life you know as youth
在我们眼里你们就是这样一无是处
with absolutely no skill to convince us otherwise.
我到任这个班级
It has been exactly one week to the day
到今天已经整整一个礼拜了
since I was assigned to teach this class,
我只想说…
and I just want to say...
所有你们需要知道的 我都已经教给你们了
I have taught you everything you need to know.
现在开始今天的授课
Now for today's lesson.
-求求你  -我们不该做这个
-Please. -We shouldn't be doing this.
-老师 我
-Oh, Teacher. Oh, ah.
-这是不对的  -老师
-This is so wrong. -Oh, Teacher. Oh.
-你真坏
-You're so bad.
-老师 我  -你会害我惹上麻烦的
-Teacher, I -- -You're gonna get me in trouble.
-我忍不住
-I can't help myself.
-看看你对我做的 -老师！
-Look what you're doing to me. -Teacher!
-老师！
-Oh, Teacher! Oh!
什么鬼？她在给她看什么？
The hell? What is she making her watch?
听起来很糟糕 非常糟糕
Whatever it is it sounds naughty -- real naughty.
下一个
Next.
你怎么一点点反应都没有？
Would it kill you to have even the tiniest reaction to this?
你是想等到自己花都谢了再进入青春期吗？
You don't want to wait until you're over the hill to hit adolescence, do you?
好吧 到此为止
Fine. I've seen all I need to.
-你们谁是下一个？-我！
Which one of you is next? I am!
呃 井出你用不着测试
Eh, I don't need to test you, Ide.
除了他还有谁？
Huh? Who's next besides him?
-我 我！-森 待会告诉我们你看了啥
-Oh! Oh! Me! -Mori, tell us what you see!
恐怕不行 我听说你必须自己看
I don't think I can. I hear you have to see for yourselves.
真无聊
-我试过了 -好恶心
What's the big deal?
-I tried! -Nasty!
是…是什么？蔬菜
W-W-What is it? Vegetables.
嘿 公主小姐 可以给我一张餐巾吗？
Hey, princess, could I get a napkin, please?
抱歉 我的鳄梨帕菲好了吗？
Sorry, but is my avocado parfait ready?
酷美酱 请帮我咖啡续杯
Hidomi-chan, more coffee, please?
她那种态度真是太棒了
She's at her best when she gives us attitude like that.
我就喜欢她用责骂的眼神俯视我
I just love it when she looks down on us with those judgy eyes.
同感
Same here.
你做得棒极了 公主小姐
You're on fire, princess.
你真的很有潜力
You have what it takes to be a champ, huh?
谢谢你来店里帮我 酷美
Thanks for helping out, Hidomi, sweetie.
帮了大忙
It really needed it today.
唔
Mm.
不过
That said,
我真的应该抓紧考虑雇人了
I should probably look into hiring someone soon.
不能因为咖啡店的事情耽误你的时间
We can't have you wasting your valuable time helping me out at the café.
这里的工厂看起来和那一个一模一样
The Plant here looks just like the other one.
发出的声音也是一样的
It makes the same sound, too.
他现在在哪呢
I wonder where he is right now.
我最近开始觉得
I've been thinking --
我们是不是不要再等他了
Maybe it's time we stopped waiting for him.
也许我们应该向前看
Maybe it's time for us to move on.
对不起 我不该说这些
I'm sorry. I shouldn't say things like this.
但是你——
But now you're --
妈妈 我——
Mommy, you know what?
嗯？
Huh?
酷美！
Hidomi!
刚才真是千钧一发呢 夫人
That was a close one, ma'am.
我向您道歉
My apologies.
要是再迟一点 她就要溢出了
A little bit more, and she would've overflowed.
溢出？
Overflowed?
奇怪了
That's strange.
-刚才的撞击应该致命才对 -致命?!
-I was sure it was a fatal hit. -Fatal hit?!
很不幸 夫人
Unfortunately, ma'am...
您的女儿平安无事
your daughter is going to be fine.
很不幸？！
That's unfortunate?!
酷美 亲爱的！
Hidomi, dear!
你还好吗？受伤了没有？
Are you okay? Are you hurt?
喂！那是我的！
Hey, that's mine!
没有在放音乐
It's not even playing anything.
还给我！
Give it back!
这是哪里来的？
Where did you get this?
这不是在大街上随随便便就能买到的东西
It's not something anyone can just walk off the street and buy.
-这是… -嗯？
-This is just... -Hmm?
这是有人送给我的
It was a gift.
你不应该戴着这个
I don't think you should wear them.
这个不适合你
They don't suit you.
假装自己听不见——
Pretending you can't hear --
你喜欢这样 对吗？
That's, like, your thing, am I right?
当你对这个世界按下了暂停键
When you hit pause on the world like that,
你的身体也会渐渐开始腐坏
your body will slowly start to rot away.
这是你所希望的吗？
Is that what you want to happen to you?
请 请等一下！
Wait a minute! You there!
夫人 您的女儿没有死
Just so you know, I take full responsibility
我会承担全部责任的
for your daughter hanging on to her life.
对了 还有一件事…
Oh, and by the way...
当心骑着 Vespa 的女人
careful of the woman on the Vespa -- for your own good.
酷美！记下她的车牌号了吗？
Hidomi! Her plates! Did you get them?
肇事逃逸！肇事逃逸！
Hit-and-run! Hit-and-run!
千万不要变成这样不负责任的大人！
Never be an irresponsible adult like that!
她是谁？她怎么回事？
Who is she? What's with her?
不知道 但是她有点帅哦
I don't know, but you got to admit she sure was cool.
哎？
Heh...
我对自己毫无期待
There is nothing I want to be.
我什么事情都不想做
There's nothing I want to do.
我甚至不知道自己想成为什么样子的人
I don't even have an image of what I want to be.
我什么都没有
I have nothing.
有的只是…无
All that exists...is zero.
那是什么？
What is that?
酷美？亲爱的？
Hidomi? Sweetie?
-妈妈！-酷美！
-Mom! Mama! -Hidomi!
雲雀…弄？呃 我…
Hiba...ji-jiri? Oh, I --
是你吗 井出？
Is that you, I-I-Ide?
它开始行动了 但这是哪一个？
It's started to move, but which is it?
-那个是什么鬼东西？-天晓得！
-What the heck is that thing? -I have no idea!
我在回家的路上 然后——
I was just walking home, and then --
-你这么晚还在外面？-呃 我有事要做
-You were out this late? -Uh, I had stuff to do,
然后那个东西就突然出现了
and that thing just suddenly appeared.
好吧 但是从哪里？
Yeah, but from where?
呃 好像是从我的脑袋里出来的
Well, it was like from my head.
好像甩掉它了
I think we lost it.
可恶 到底怎么回事？
Holy shit! What the hell's going on?!
别过来！
No!
我明白了 原来如此
I see now. That's how it is, huh?
喂！她人在哪？
Hey! Where is she --
把那个东西从你身体里拉出来的家伙？
the one who pulled that out of you?!
回答我！你被撞了吧？
Answer me! You were hit, weren't you?
是不是一个骑着 Vespa 的女人？
Was it a woman on a Vespa?
Ves...pa?
喂
Hey.
你是谁？井出他没事吧？
Who are you? And Ide...is he okay?
我会尽量给他治疗的
I'm going to do what I can for his wounds.
-你回家吧 -等一下
-You get home safe, okay? -Wait a minute.
顺带一提
Oh, by the way,
那个很适合你 赞
that thing looks good on you. Nice.
『Little Busters』— the Pillows
吓死我了
Thank goodness.
你没有受伤真是太好了
Well, I'm so glad nothing actually happened to you,
酷美 亲爱的
Hidomi, dear.
嗯
Hmm.
妈妈可担心了
You know, Mommy was so worried
以为你要离家出走呢
that maybe you decided to run away from home.
With the kids sing out the future
孩子们歌唱着未来
Maybe, kids don't need the masters
也许孩子们不需要主人
但是如果真的要离家出走
But if youwere going to run away,
一定要搞得轰轰烈烈哦
you should do it with a bang.
Just waiting for the little busters
只要等小混蛋们到来
但是千万别把房子给砸了
Just please try not to break the house next time,
好吗？-嗯
all right, sweetie. -Mm.
这——这是？
Bu-- But why?
她想要为昨天的事情负责
She's taking responsibility for yesterday.
自我介绍一下吧
Please introduce yourself.
我是仁由
I'm Jinyu.
我靠！那些绷带是怎么回事？
Whoa! What's with all those bandages?
你怎么了井出？
Yeah, what happened to you, Ide?
不知道该怎么跟你们说
Man, I don't even know where to start.
发生了很多 很多事…
A lot of stuff happened, quite a lot of stuff.
“很多事”？
"A lot of stuff"?
那算什么？
What kind of answer is that?
这跟没说有什么区别
That's like a non-answer answer.
在你们开始合理又灾难性的新的一天之前
Today, as you start on your understandably
时下的少年少女们
disastrous day as modern-day youth,
我作为现实生活中决定性的赢家
I, as someone who is the clear winner in life structurally,
要告诉你们很重要的事情
would like to present to you something very important --
关于如何在这个世界上生存
the "this and that" on how to live in this universe.
■
B班（23）
U.Beviaqua: 话说 Takeshi 是不是
喜欢 Emily？
KAs: 真的吗？！
Akihiro: 真的是这样吗？！
St: 我都不知道！！
RYO: 现在已经 Free 了吧？
U.Beviaqua: 机会！！
KAs: 机——会！！
Akihiro: 加油！！
U.Beviaqua: 过了这个村就没了这个店！
U.Beviaqua: 可不能放过这次机会
TK: 诶？
TK: 这是在说我吗？
U.Beviaqua: 会去的吧
你们会被测试
You will be tested on it,
甚至每天的生活本身就是测试
insomuch as every day in itself is a test.
-对 就是你 - 呃…
-Yes. You over there. -Uh...
回答错误
Wrong answer.
■
B班（23）
U.Beviaqua: 反正 Free 了
TK: 哈？
Akihiro: 是的 因为 Free 了
安东: Free!
TK: 喂 等等
U.Beviaqua: 你是不会做出不好好利用
Free 的那种没劲事吧？
安东: 那么——Take 酱怎么做？
TK: 你们这些人
U.Beviaqua: 只能利用好 Free 了！
Akihiro: 好好利用吧！！
安东: 这样美味的 Free 可是很难得的哦！
KAs: 同意
安东: Free 好啊，Free 真是好！
U.Beviaqua: Freefree 喔 Freefree
KAs: Furifuri
Akihiro: Furifuri?
安东: Furikuri?
我最近想明白了
I figured out something recently.
与其为了随机的问题
Instead of preparing a concrete answer
准备具体的答案 我认为
to random questions, I have come to the conclusion
并不存在你们的生存之道
that there is no real way to live,
对于你们这些只要
not for those of you who exist contently
蠢动着动物般的性欲就能获得满足
by only jerking your animalistic sexual urges to fulfillment,
在我们眼里一无是处的人
and you who have absolutely no skill to convince us otherwise.
我付出了那么多 但是成果少得可怜
I gave so, so much, but there was very little output.
微不足道只能供人玩乐的小虫子对我毫无价值
I have no use for the tiny pieces of scum bugs that have been toyed with.
Furi…kuri…
Fooly...Cooly...
听你们老师一言 我不希望你们成为不存在的孩子
Listen to your teacher. I have no desire for all of you to wind up as nonexistent youth.
我要让你们都变成宇宙级别的大人
What I want is for all of you to become adults on a cosmological scale!
■
B班（23）
mi-: FuriKuri
ichiro-: furi Kuri
kanako: Furi Kuri！！？
daidai: FLCL
kome: FuriKuri
竹尾: furikuri
(^o^): FL--CL--
wa: FuriKuri
ASADA: f l c l！
oshiyama: Furi！Kuri！
sada: FLCLFLCLFLCL
KUBO: Furi Kuri！
kiyo: Furi Kuri！！
arai: FLCL！！
（FLCL的假名和英文刷屏）
你不需要翅膀也能在宇宙探险
You don't need wings to go venture out into the universe.
谁会需要长翅膀的四轮汽车？
Who would ride a four-wheeled car with wings, anyway?
你们不可以变成那样的大人
You must not become that kind of adult.
明白了吗？你们不需要四个轮子！
Do you understand me? You do not need four wheels!
你们只需要两个——就像池塘里的底栖鱼一样
You only need two -- like a bottom-feeding fish in a pond,
在低垂的柳树下面聚成一群
gathering underneath a weeping willow tree.
Furi Kuri 和 FLCL 的刷屏
你们的下方有强大的重力
There's a lot of gravity underneath all of you...
...so stand up! Be as adequate as you can, a complete mess,
所以站起来！你们就越差强人意越好 最好变成一团糟
生来注定平庸！
born to be mild!
这就对了 我想要的终于要出现了
That's right, the real one's finally appearing.